## Ayan Chowdhury

#### Software Developer

A passionate Software Developer with 1 year of Industry Experience as Backend and Android developer with apps on Google play, hands-on experience in C++, Python, Elixir, API development, Android, Kotlin. A quick learner and open to learning any new technology.

# ayan.chowdhury2050@gmail.com 8961529749 kolkata, India linkedin.com/in/ayanc-97

https://github.com/GhAc-2017

https://leetcode.com/acloj97/

http://ayanchowdhury.live/

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer Kreeti Technologies

09/2019 – Present Achievements/Tasks

Kolkata

- Schoolm (A complete School Management Solution)
   Created Medicine, Uniform, Book, Staff Attendance related
   API, Tests and Documentation written in Elixir in Phoenix
   Framework for project Schoolm a Product of Kreeti
   technologies.
- GoGal( A women helper multi-functional social media application) Designed and developed Android App in project GoGal with ownership. I was involved in every aspect from Application Design Implementation to defining the Workflow of the project and collaborated in a team of 3 people and delivered a complete app from scratch via research and Agile development.

*Major Contribution* - Lead the app development with MVVM architecture in kotlin and emphasis on User Experience, performance and developed User Authentication, OTP Auth, Notification System Building.

- TruckersApp( A Truckers' helper application for finding them optimal delivery routes) Created and delivered complete Android app with Rails backend and hosted on aws for company's Demonstration.
- Digimep(The Digital Cloud-Based Process Workflow Service for Site Surveys) Built Api and Tests, Documentation for project Digimep a survey application.

*Major contribution* - Incorporating New External API features in application, Improving existing app efficiency, Increase Test coverage from 26.33% to 34.56%(still working on it), wrote detailed documentations and added API code for different client requirements.

#### SmartGardener

Implemented various features of Smartgardener android app following test and made sure of the complete application unit test passes

#### **Software Developer Intern** ImageIDGP-ITRA,MediaLabAsia

Kalyani

09/2018 - 06/2019

Achievements/Tasks

- Researched and developed every aspects of the Android app lifecycle from design and planning through deployment and post-launch support.
- Published 2 Apps on the Google Play during my Internship Period.

## **EDUCATION**

#### B.Tech CGPA-8.75

Kalyani Government Engineering College

08/2015 - 07/2019

Courses

Data Structure and Algorithms, DBMS, OS

Higher Secondary(90%) , Secondary(91.14%) Belgharia High School

SKILLS

Python C++ Andro

Android Java-

Java-Basics Ko

Kotlin

Elixir

Firebase Phoenix

Docker

er | Rea

React-Native

Rails

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### FrienChat (10/2017 – 06/2019)

 Used Android, Java, Firebase to Build that Fully featured chat app which features all the functionalities like sharing any document format, chats, Notification, Group Messaging, Channel messaging

#### **SplitWise**

 An expense sharing application in c++ where you can add your expenses and split it among different people. The app keeps balances between people as in who owes how much to whom. https://github.com/GhAc-2017/SplitWise

#### Snake Ladder App

 A snake ladder console application using c++, with multiple player and https://github.com/GhAc-2017/mock-machine-coding-1

#### ProjectyTracker (06/2019 - 08/2019)

 A Project Management web application like Pivotal Tracker with Outlook Login Option, using Ruby On Rails

...More other project details in http://ayanchowhury.live

### **ACHIEVEMENTS/ACTIVITIES**

 Core Member at KeyGenCoders -the official Programming Club of KGEC

In our Programming club we arrange seminars , events to Enrich the culture of coding

• During Internship Published App on Playstore which has a over 5000 downloads and 4.7 Ratings

App published under ICAR-NRC on Pig https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.icar.actech.swineapp&hl=en

 Converted a Desktop Software to a Fully Featured Android App

It was a Desktop Software regarding Protozoa Parasitic Diseases in animal I build an android app which does the same in Mobile phone

• Teach a group of students DS and Algo to achieve their placement goal